Guide to the Montana Gerontology Society Records 1982-2018
Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, The University of Montana--Missoula
Montana Gerontology Society Records
1982-2018
University of Montana, Mansfield Library, Archives and Special Collections The University of Montana—Missoula Missoula, MT 59812 406-243-2053 http://www.lib.umt.edu/asc library.archives@umontana.edu
Mss 881
Montana Gerontology Society
1.5 linear feet and 30.82 megabytes of digital material
The Montana Gerontology Society is dedicated to enhancing professional development and understanding among providers of services, seniors, volunteers, researchers, educators, students, and others associated with the field of aging. This collection include the Society’s administrative documents, conference materials, photographs, and newsletters from 1982-2018.
Historical Note
The Montana Gerontology Society was organized in 1982 and provides opportunities for individuals interested in gerontology to share common concerns and ideas. The Society is dedicated to enhancing professional development and understanding among providers of services, seniors, volunteers, researchers, educators, students, and others associated with the field of aging. Among the Society’s objectives are encouraging networking among people in the field, and developing training for professionals and the public. The organization is known for its annual conferences that have been held since 1983.
The Montana Gerontology Society collection includes records related to the business of the Society, newsletters published by the organization, and materials related to its annual conferences.
This collection is divided into three series:
Series I: Administrative Materials, 1982-2018, 0.25 linear feet and 1.76 megabytes digital files
Sub-series I: Administrative Documents, 1982-2018, 0.25 linear feet
Sub-series II: Photographs, 1997-1998 and undated, 1 folder and 1.76 megabytes digital files
Series II: Conference Materials, 1983-2017, 1.0 linear foot and 29.06 megabytes digital files
Sub-series I: Conference Materials, 1983-2017, 1.0 linear foot
Sub-series II: Schedules, 1984-2014, 20.91 megabytes digital files
Sub-series III: Photographs, 1984-1993, 8.15 megabytes digital files
Series III: Newsletters, 1983-2017, 0.25 linear feet
Researchers must use collection in accordance with the policies of Archives and Special Collections, the Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, and The University of Montana-Missoula.
These materials were held by board members of the Montana Gerontology Society until their donation to the Archives.
Mindy Renfro, former president of the Montana Gerontology Society, donated the bulk of the collection to archives on January 8, 2015. Additional materials were donated by Gayle Hudgins in December 2018.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Montana Gerontology Society--Archives
Gerontology--Vocational guidance--Montana; Gerontology--Montana--Congresses; Older people--Montana--Social conditions; Aging--Social aspects--Montana
Montana
- Administrative Materials, 1982-2018; Series I; 0.25 linear feet and 1.76 megabytes digital files
  This series contains administrative documents and photographs related to the Montana Gerontology Society. Documents include minutes and by-laws. Photographs are of board members.
  - Administrative Documents, 1982-2018; Subseries 1; 0.25 linear feet
    Files are arranged in alphabetical order
    - Accomplishments, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 1/1)
    - Board of Directors, Lists, 1982-2002 and 2017-2018 (Box-folder 1/2)
    - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1983-1987 (Box-folder 1/3)
    - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1989-1993 (Box-folder 1/4)
    - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1994-2010 (Box-folder 1/5)
    - Brief History, Undated (Box-folder 1/6)
    - Bylaws, 1982-1989, 2005, 2008 and 2012 (Box-folder 1/7)
    - Correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 1/8)
    - Financial Audits and Reports, 1984-1994 (Box-folder 1/9)
    - Goals, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 1/10)
    - Guidelines, 2005 (Box-folder 1/11)
    - Human Resources Materials, 1986-1994, 2002, 2008 and Undated (Box-folder 1/12)
    - Letterhead, Business Cards, and Envelopes, Undated (Box-folder 1/13)
    - Membership Application, Undated (Box-folder 1/14)
    - Mission Statement and Calendar, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 1/15)
  - Photographs, 1997-1998 and undated; Subseries 2; 1 folder and 1.76 megabytes digital files
    Files are arranged chronologically.
    - Former Board Members, Photographs, 1986 and Undated (Box-folder 1/16)
    - Former Board Members, Photographs, 1997-1998 (Digital image Digital Image)
    - Former Board Members, Photographs, Undated (Digital image Digital Image)
    - Former Board Members, Photographs, Undated (Digital image Digital Image)
- Conference Materials, 1983-2017; Series II; 1.0 linear foot and 29.06 megabytes digital files
  This series contains materials related to the Montana Gerontology Society's annual conferences and is divided into three sub-series: Conference Materials, Schedules and Photographs.
  - Conference Materials, 1983-2017; Subseries 1; 1.0 linear foot
    This subseries is arranged alphabetically by folder title.
    - Administrative Documents, 2008 (Box-folder 1/17)
    - Administrative Documents, 2009 (Box-folder 1/18)
    - Administrative Documents, 2010 (Box-folder 1/19)
    - Administrative Documents, 2011 (Box-folder 1/20)
    - Administrative Documents, 2012 (Box-folder 2/1)
    - Clippings, 1984-1989 and 2007 (Box-folder 2/2)
    - Meeting Minutes, 1984-1989 and 2000 (Box-folder 2/3)
    - Miscellaneous Photographs, 1992 and Undated (Box-folder 2/4)
    - Programs, 1983-1986 (Box-folder 2/5)
    - Programs, 1987-1992 (Box-folder 2/6)
    - Programs, 1993-1996 (Box-folder 2/7)
    - Programs, 1997-2001 (Box-folder 2/8)
    - Programs, 2002-2005 (Box-folder 3/1)
    - Programs, 2006-2012 (Box-folder 3/2)
    - Programs, 2013-2014 and 2016-2017 (Box-folder 3/3)
    - Scrapbook, 1983 (Box-folder 3/4)
    - Scrapbook, 1984 (Box-folder 3/5)
    - Scrapbook, 1985 (Box-folder 3/6)
    - Scrapbook, 1986 (Box-folder 3/7)
    - Scrapbook, 1987 (Box-folder 3/8)
    - Scrapbook, 1988 (Box-folder 3/9)
    - Scrapbook, 1989 (Box-folder 3/10)
    - Scrapbook, 1990 (Box-folder 3/11)
  - Schedules, 1984-2014; Subseries 2; 20.91 megabytes digital files
    - Schedules, 1984-1989 (Electronic file Electronic File)
    - Schedules, 1990-1999 (Electronic file Electronic File)
    - Schedules, 2000-2009 (Electronic file Electronic File)
    - Schedules, 2010-2014 (Electronic file Electronic File)
  - Photographs, 1984-1993; Subseries 3; 8.15 megabytes digital files
    - Photographs, 1984 (Digital image Digital Image)
    - Photographs, 1985 (Digital image Digital Image)
    - Photographs, 1986 (Digital image Digital Image)
    - Photographs, 1986 (Digital image Digital Image)
    - Photographs, 1987 (Digital image Digital Image)
    - Photographs, 1988 (Digital image Digital Image)
    - Photographs, 1988 (Digital image Digital Image)
    - Photographs, 1989 (Digital image Digital Image)
    - Photographs, 1992 (Digital image Digital Image)
    - Photographs, 1992 (Digital image Digital Image)
    - Photographs, 1993 (Digital image Digital Image)
    - Photographs, 1993 (Digital image Digital Image)
- Newsletters, 1983-2017; Series III; 0.25 linear feet
  - Newsletters, 1983-1991 (Box-folder 4/1)
  - Newsletters, 1992-2001 (Box-folder 4/2)
  - Newsletters, 2002-2015 and 2017 (Box-folder 4/3)